Manel Djehiche

| AVASCRIPT DEVELOPER | DATA SCIENTIST

<u>maneldje81@gmail.com</u>

O Bab Ezzouar, Algiers, 16042, Algeria

+213 0552230871

Details

Driving license Nationality
Yes Algerian

Date / Place of birth 25-09-1997 / Algiers

Profile

I am principally a JavaScript Web Developer with 5 years of experience and a Data Scientist using python with 3 years of experience, I worked with many other technologies like Java, C++, and PHP.

For web development, I am a back-end and front-end programmer using NodeJs and ReactJs having the knowledge to choose the best conception of the database [relational or no relational].

Speaking about Artificial intelligence, I have a good level in Deep learning, Nlp, Machine learning, problem resolution, problem optimization, and data mining. I can do data collection and data cleaning, and then build models that help you taking the right decision.

I have worked in many companies which allows me to get strong expertise in team-working, social intelligence, problem resolution, how to discuss the functionalities with the customer, reporting, and choosing the best technologies in order to get the best results possible.

My latest job is as a full stack web developer in Sonelgaz company, it's an international Algerian company that is responsible for sharing the electricity and the gas in all the country, that gave me a good experience in graphs and how to treat complicated problems with high complexity.

Employment History

Full stack web developer, Dz-Canada [Remote - CD], Québec

July 2018 — December 2018

- · Creation of dynamic web application using PHP, MySQL,
- Customizing HTML, CSS, BOOTSTRAP AND REACT templates depending the the need of the client.
- Building E-commerce websites using OpenCART.

Full Stack Javascript Developer, LAKKINI [CD], Algeria

April 2021 — November 2022

- I used to create Restful API using Nodejs, MongoDB on the server-side.
- On the client-side using REACT, HTML, CSS.

Microservices with Golang & React developer, Emplorium [Remote - CD], London

June 2022 — December 2022

- I used to create GraphQL API using Golang, Postgres.
- On the client-side, working with React.

· Handling microservices architecture and how to define multiple services.

Deep Learning and Machine Learning developer, Freelance tasks

April 2020 — Present

I used to take projects in AI using machine learning and deep learning tools.

- Data collection using web scraping from websites.
- · Cleaning data and preparing it for machine learning.
- · Creating smart models with TensorFlow, Sklearn, Pandas, and Keras Libraries with Python.

Javascript Web developer, Elit Sonelgaz [CI], Algiers

December 2021 — Present

- 1- Handling graphs and high complexity networks.
- 2- Real problem resolution and optimization.
- 3- Back-end using NodeJs and python.
- 4- Front-end using ReactJs.

Education

Master 2 in Artificial Intelligence, University of Science and Technology Houari Boumediene, Algiers

September 2018 — June 2020

I have got huge expertise in Artificial intelligence from my university in different domains, including data mining, vision computer, NLP, problem resolution, algorithm optimization, and complexity.

Licence in computer systems, University of algiers, Algiers

September 2015 — June 2018

I have learned many things related to web development and database structure, including MySQL database, UML for conception, How to choose the best architecture for database related to the problem, web application, understanding very well how processors and pcs work which allows me to know what data structure to choose in my programs and algorithm.

Links

Linkdin Github Projects

Skills

PHP CSS HTML5 SQL jQuery MySQL MongoDB Git Python Java HTML & CSS Node.js **Conflict Resolution** React JavaScript **Typescript**

A JAX Postgres

Tensorflow, Keras, Pandas and SKlearn Golang

Languages

English French
Arabic

Internships

Deep Learning Researcher, RESEARCH CENTRE FOR SCIENTIFIC AND TECHNICAL INFORMATION, Algiers

January 2020 — June 2020

I have built multiple deep learning and machine learning models in the project "Sentiment Analysis Algerian Dialect". I went through different steps, let me resume them for you.

- Data Collection from Facebook
- Having done deep research of related works then I have invented my own solution by contributing to the subject of 'Sentiment Analysis Arabic Dialect'
- · Data cleaning
- Implementing common models of deep learning and machine learning then proposing my own model by combining different models, then comparing different architecture

Resolution of communication problem between two applications using Web Service, General Directorate of Douane, Algiers

January 2018 — June 2018

I have created a web service that automatically allows data exchange between two websites using Java, MySQL, and Bootstrap.

Participation in Chatbot system, Emplorium

August 2021 — December 2021

I have participated in a chatbot website that allows communication with customers.

- Creation of multiples agents accounts.
- A customer can ask any question in the chat.
- Each agent can answer customers' questions. So agents between them work at the same time without any problem.

Participation in Scholar management system, Lakkini

Courses

ReactJs, Zero to Hero academy

Deep Learnin in NLP, Coursera

Machine Learning, Coursera